프리티 리틀 라이어스 지난 이야기
NARRATOR: Previously on
Pretty Little Liars...
- 드레스 입고 있어
- 앨리슨은 어때?
- She's getting dressed.
- How is she?
자기 엄마의 장례식에 갈 참이야
걔가 어떨 거라고 생각해?
She's going to her mom's
funeral. How do you think she is?
문제는 누가 알리의 엄마를
스펜서네 마당에 묻었냐는 거 아니야?
Question is who buried Ali's
mom in Spencer's backyard?
오빠가 이걸 볼 필요가 있어요
I think you need to look at this.
제이슨이 정말 너희 아빠를
Jason actually told you
믿어서는 안 된다고 말했어?
that you shouldn't trust your own father?
그는 마치 D부인이
우리 아빠에게
He made it seem like Mrs.
D was writing to my dad,
더 이상 당신을 보호할 수 없어요
라고 쓴 것처럼 보이게 했어
"I can't protect you anymore."
- 우린 싸웠던 거야
- 그게 우리에게 무슨 차이지?
- We're done fighting.
- Which makes us what?
우린 친구가 될 수 있을 거야
Maybe we'll be friends.
뉴욕에서 있었던 일이
너를 묻어버릴거야
The truth will bury you
in a New York minute.
내가 그 문자를 보냈어
I sent that text.
난 숨지 않을 거야,
네가 숨지 않았듯이
I don't have to hide, you do.
그리고 넌 죽은 상태였던 게
더 나았을 거야
And you're gonna wish you stayed dead.
넌 내 머리를 염색하게 했고
나에게 앨리슨의 옷을 입게 했으며
You made me dye my hair,
you made me wear her clothes,
앨리슨처럼
걷고, 말하게 만들었어
you made me walk like her, talk like her.
내가 너를 알리로
업그레이드 시켜주지 않았더라면
If I hadn't given you the Ali upgrade,
너는 어디에 있을까?
where would you be?
이번엔 달라요
Not the same.
변화할 때예요
It's time for a change.
네가 우리들에게 원하는 게
정확히 뭔데?
Exactly what is it you want us to do?
우리가 단결하길 원해
I want us to stick together.
우리가 거대해질 수록
앨리슨은 심하게 무너질테니까
The bigger we are, the harder she falls.
샤나의 일에 대해선
걱정하지 않아도 돼요
You don't have to worry about Shana.
그녀는 죽었어요
나 때문에요
She's dead, because I'm responsible.
너 때문이라는 게
무슨 말이지?
What do you mean "responsible"?
내가 그녀를 죽였다는 말이죠
I mean that I killed her.
서. 더이상 도망칠 필요 없어
Stop. You don't need to run anymore.
A는 죽었어
'A' is gone.
맘에 안드는구나
You hate it.
아냐, 싫어하지 않아
정말로 맘에 들어
No, I don't hate it. I
actually really like it.
I'm just confused why the sudden impulse.
왜 갑자기 충동적이 됐나해서
어리둥절했을 뿐이야
I wanted to be spontaneous.
충동적이 되길 원했어
한나, 넌
충동적이지 않다구
Hanna, you're not spontaneous.
넌 손톱 손질을
바꾸기 전에
You make a Pinterest board
핀터레스트 보드를 만들잖아
before you change your nail polish.
샤나 프링
_
무슨 일이야?
What's wrong?
아무 것도 아냐
Nothing.
한나
Hanna.
이거 샤나 거였어
This was Shana's.
뭐라구?
What?
도로 두자
Let's just put it back.
아냐, 아냐, 아냐, 잠깐만
No, no, no. Hold on a second.
세상에, 얘가 밑줄쳤던 걸 봐
Oh my God, look what she underlined.
"It is a curious subject
whether hatred and love
증오와 사랑의 바탕이
같은지, 다른지는
be not the same thing at bottom.
궁금한 주제이다
그 대상자가 사라짐으로서
Each leaves the passionate lover,
or the no less passionate
hater, forlorn and desolate
열정적인 사랑이나
열정적인 증오를 내려 놓으면
허망하고 쓸쓸하다
by the withdrawal of his subject."
Aria, it's probably
just a school assignment.
아리아, 이건
학교 과제였을 거야
No, this is about Ali and Jenna and us.
아니야, 이건
알리와 제나와 우리에 관한 거야
이건 A에 관한 거야
This is about being 'A.'
아니, 넌 샤나에 관해
잊어야 하는데도
No, this is about you trying to paw
샤나의 물건을 통해
긁어 부스럼을 내려는 거야
through Shana's things
when you should be trying
to forget about her.
Well, there might be something in here.
어쨌든, 여기에 분명
뭔가가 있다고
그만 해
Just stop.
누가 주홍글씨를 내팽겨 친 거야
Who's throwing out The Scarlet Letter.
난 이 책을 좋아했었지
I loved this book.
너희들은 알리를 위해
이걸 가져가야 할 걸
Maybe you should get it for Ali.
걔가 학교로 돌아올 계획이라면
이걸 따라잡아야 할 걸
Since she is planning
on coming back to school,
she probably needs it to catch up.
걔는 복사본으로 구할 거야
She'll get her own copy.
이건 내가 가져가야겠다
I'll take this one.
샤나는 이게
필요치 않을 거야
Shana won't be needing it.
샤나는 조지아로
전학간 거 맞지?
She transferred back to Georgia, right?
몰라
I don't know.
우린 거의 그애를
기억하지 못해
We barely remember the girl.
Who could blame you?
누가 너희를 탓하겠니?
여기서는 사람들이
너무 빨리 왔다가 가거든
People come and go so quickly around here.
샤나는 가고, 알리가 오고
Shana gone, Ali back.
한 소녀가 나가고
다른 소녀가 들어오지
One girl checks out and
another one checks in.
머리 잘 됐구나
Nice hair.
Pretty Little Liars S05 X E04
Thrown From the Ride
♪ Got a secret ♪
♪ Can you keep it? ♪
♪ Swear this one you'll save ♪
♪ Better lock it in your pocket ♪
♪ Taking this one to the grave ♪
♪ If I show you then I know ♪
영자막 chamallow
♪ You won't tell what I said ♪
♪ 'Cause two can keep a secret ♪
한글자막 L - H
♪ If one of them is dead ♪
얘야
Hey.
배가 고프다면 와플 있다
There's waffles if you're hungry.
그건 뭐니?
What you got there?
자선기부할 옷들이예요
Clothes for Goodwill.
알리, 한동안 미뤄두는 게
좋은 생각이지 않을까?
Al, do you think it's a good idea
to hold off for a bit?
I wouldn't want you to give away
네 엄마의 물건을
내놓는 건 원치 않는다
something of your mom's that
you might regret later on.
넌 나중에 후회할 거야
These aren't mom's. They're mine.
이건 엄마 물건이 아니예요
제 거예요
I feel like I needed a clean slate.
지워버리고 싶어요
알겠다. 하지만 조금은
성급한 결정 아니니?
Okay. But do you feel like
you're rushing this a bit?
It might be nice to have
some familiar things.
친숙한 물건들을 가지고 있는 게
좋을 것 같은데 말이다
이미 이 옷들은
제게 맞지 않아요
I've grown out of this stuff already.
저는 2년 전과
같은 사람이 아니예요
I'm not the same person I was 2 years ago.
Oh, I need some things
before I go back to school.
오, 학교로 돌아가기 전에
필요한 것들이 있어요
노트패드랑
새로운 책가방이랑요
Notepads, a new backpack.
학교라고?
School?
영원히 제 방에
머물순 없잖아요
I can't stay in my room forever.
그건 도움이 되지 않아요
It's not helping.
30살이 되기 전에
졸업하려면
And I need to go back if I want to graduate
돌아가야지요
before I'm 30.
I want you to have that fresh start
난 네가 새로운
시작을 했으면 한다
우리에 대해
이야기하지 않는 곳에서 말이다
that we're talking about.
우리가 여기에 남는 것이 가능한지
정말 모르겠구나
But I really don't see how
that's possible if we stay here.
You want to move?
이사가고 싶으세요?
No. No, I need my friends.
아뇨. 안 돼요
난 친구가 필요해요
Well, you'll still see them.
여전히 걔네들을 볼 수 있을 거야
내가 이사한 곳은
여기서 멀지 않아
The place I moved into isn't that far away.
그 애들이 와서
여름을 보낼 수 있을 게다
Maybe the girls can come
and spend the summer.
Dad.
아빠
제발요. 그러지 마세요
Please. Don't.
I can't have my friends
taken away from me, too.
다시 친구들을
떠나 보낼 순 없어요
이건 폭파현장에
살고 있는 것 같아
It's like living in the
middle of a demolition site.
저들이 모든 걸 파괴했다구
They destroyed everything.
Absolutely everything.
완전 모든 걸 말이야
Mom, did you sleep down here last night?
엄마, 어제밤에
여기서 주무셨어요?
I wouldn't call it sleep.
잤다고 말할 수 없어
Every time I closed my eyes
눈 감을 때마다
삽으로 긁어내는 소리를 들었거든
I could hear the scraping of the shovels.
Do you remember when you told me
아빠와 언니가
이상한 행동을 한다고
that Dad and Melissa
had been acting strange?
제게 말하셨던 거 기억하세요?
Yes.
그래
Okay, well the other day
좋아요, 며칠 전에
언니가 나에게
Melissa tried to tell me something,
뭔가 중요한 걸 말하려 했는데
아빠가 언니를 말렸어요
something important and Dad stopped her.
And I think that it has
to do with Ali's mom.
그리고 그건 알리의
엄마에 관한 거였다고 생각해요
오, 스펜서...
Oh, Spencer...
아뇨, 뭔가 잘못된 걸 아시잖아요
No, you know something's wrong.
Okay. I can tell that you know.
좋아요. 엄마가 아는 걸
말할 수 있어요
They're hiding something.
두 사람은 뭔가
숨기고 있어요
네 언니에게 얘기했었다
I spoke to your sister.
걔가 유일하게 숨긴 건
The only thing that she's been hiding
렌과 다시
함께하게 된 거였어
is getting back together with Wren.
That's why she avoided Toby.
그게 토비를 피한 이유야
언니는 다른 비밀을
갖고 있다구요
She's keeping other secrets.
(footsteps approaching)
Morning.
안녕
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
아님 지금 내가
해명해야 되는 일이야?
Or should I say what's the matter now?
제시카에 대해
얘기하고 있었어요
We were just talking about Jessica.
How upsetting it is.
얼마나 가슴이 아픈 일인지
Of course, you're upset.
물론 당신은 가슴 아프지
We all are.
우리 모두 그렇지
How much longer is our yard
언제까지 우리 마당이
범죄현장으로 있어야 하죠?
going to remain a crime scene?
They said they'd be done
by the end of the day.
오늘이면 끝난다고 하던데
느긋해져 보라구
Try to relax about it.
You too, Spence.
너도 마찬가지다, 스펜서
이번 주말에 마당을
다시 단장하는데
Do you think we could hire Toby
this weekend to help us replant the yard?
토비가 우리를 돕도록
고용할 수 있을까?
토비는 일하러
길포드에 갔어요
Toby's on a job at Guilford.
우리끼리 할 수 있는 일이
아닌 것 같은데
I don't think we can do this by ourselves.
저기, 엄마,
도와줄 사람을 찾아볼게요
Look, Mom, I will find somebody to help.
이 얘기나 하실래요?
Can we please just talk about this?
아니. 아니다
No. No.
그 얘기는 하고 싶지 않아
I don't want to talk about it.
이웃이 우리 마당에서
살해당한 채로 발견됐어
Our next door neighbor was found murdered
in our backyard.
이런 경험은 꿈에서라도
말하고 싶지 않구나
Surreal doesn't even begin
to describe this experience.
우리가 통제할 수 있는
일에 집중하자구나, 알겠니?
Let's just focus on what
we can control, okay?
넌 순해빠졌어
You're being naive.
We can't just call the thing off.
우린 그냥 취소할 수 없어
분명 할 수 있어
Sure we can.
오늘 아침, 네 콘플레이크에
누가 침이라도 뱉은 거야?
Did somebody spit in your
cornflakes this morning?
왜 갑자기 꽁무니를 빼는 건데?
Why are you suddenly bugging out?
그런게 아냐
I'm not.
I'm just having second thoughts.
다만 재고해볼 뿐이야
그애는 지하실에
갖혀 있었어, 알겠니?
She was held in a basement, okay?
Alison was kidnapped and blindfolded
앨리슨은 납치당하고
눈이 가려졌었는데
내가 무얼 한다는 건
생각하고 싶지도 않아
and I don't even want
to think about what else.
걔가 충분히 처벌을 받았다고
생각하지 않아?
Hasn't the universe punished her enough?
우리가 하려는 건
처벌이 아니야
What we're doing isn't punishment,
it's a preventative measure.
예방차원이지
That's semantics.
그건 의미론적인 말이야
내가 이런 말을 할 거라곤
절대 생각하지 않았는데
I never thought I'd say this,
걔가 애처롭게 느껴진다구
but I feel bad for her.
It's hard to still see Ali as the devil
지옥에서 탈출해 왔는데
알리를 여전히
악마로 보는 건 곤란해
when she just escaped from the hell.
What if I told you that her abduction story
걔가 납치된 이야기가
그저 지어낸 이야기라고 말한다면 어쩔 건데?
is just that, a story?
No one would lie about something like that.
누구도 그런 이야기를
거짓말하진 않아
She did.
걔는 그랬어
그리고 내가 증명할 수 있어
And I can prove it.
58 seconds?
58초라고? 겨우 그거야?
내가 날라다닌 것처럼 느꼈는데
That's all? It felt like I was flying.
Yeah, your technique is
so much better though.
그래, 하지만 기술은
많이 좋아졌어
계속해서 체력을
늘리도록 해보자
Let's just keep working on
increasing your strength.
내일 만날까?
You want to meet up tomorrow?
Yeah.
그래
가족들을 만나봐야 하지만
I have to check in with my family,
괜찮을 거야
but it should be cool.
오, 알겠다
토요일이었네
Oh, right. It's Saturday.
- 네가 필요하다면...
- 아냐, 여전히 할 일이 있어
Do you need to...
No, I can still make it.
I'm pretty much doing everything
집에 있는 시간을 피하기 위해
내가 할 수 있는 모든 일을 하고 있어
I can to avoid spending time at home.
What's going on?
무슨 일인데?
Besides my mom giving me the third degree?
우리 엄마가 내게 질문공세를
퍼붓는 걸 제외하면? 없어
Nothing.
내 친구 알리가
돌아온 이후로
Ever since my friend Ali came back
우리 엄마가 하시는 일은
내게 질문을 던지시는 게 전부야
all my mom does is ask me questions.
그리고 질문을 안 하실 땐
And when she's not asking me questions,
얘기하실 걸 기다리시면서
나를 응시하고 계셔
she's staring at me,
waiting for me to talk.
그래서 난
엄마로부터 벗어나기 위해
So I've started taking extra long showers
just to get away from her.
샤워를 오래 하고 있지
When the hot water runs out, I'm screwed.
온수가 떨어져버렸을 땐
완전히 맛이 갔었다구
It's kind of natural though for her
질문이 있다는 건
엄마로서는
당연한 생각이야
to have questions.
I would never ask mine,
나라면 내 아이에게 질문하지 않을걸
하지만 내게 애가 있다는 말은 아니야
but it doesn't mean I don't have them.
What time tomorrow?
내일 몇 시에 볼까?
(phone ringing)
앨리슨
Let's meet up same time as today.
오늘이랑 같은 시간에 만나자
오, 미안
Oh. Sorry.
No problem.
괜찮아
It's better than sitting in the cafeteria.
카프테리아에 앉아있으니
한결 나은 걸
설마
Not really.
우린 여전히 *프릭쇼라구
기형이나 기괴한 동물을 보여주는 쇼
We're still a freak show.
Now we're just a freak
show in natural light.
지금 우린 자연 조명 아래에 있는
프릭쇼일 뿐이야
I feel like we're lobsters
in the tank at a restaurant.
난 우리가 음식점 물탱크 안에 있는
랍스터가 된 기분이야
You know, the ones that you stare at to see
있잖아, 네가 먹으려는 놈
하나를 골라서
which one you want to eat.
그놈을 쳐다보는 거야
And then you see the lobster
with like the chewed off claw
그리고서 깨먹을 망치를 가지고
그 랍스터를 보는 거지
그리고 그 랍스터...
and then the rubber band is...
Hanna, we're not lobsters.
한나, 우린 랍스터가 아니야
Relax.
진정해
안녕
Hey.
Oh, my God.
오, 이런
Guys.
얘들아
모나는 정말로
나를 기겁하게 해
She is seriously freaking me out.
She knows that we were in New York.
쟤는 우리가
뉴욕에 있었던 걸 알아
재는 알리를 협박했다구
She threatened Ali.
샤나에 관한 것 역시 안다면?
What if she knows about Shana, too?
아리아, 넌 당장 정신적인 *셀피를 찍어야 돼
사진을 찍어 SNS에 올리는 것
Aria, look, you need to take
a psychological selfie right now.
You're letting your paranoia
get the better of you.
넌 편집증에 빠져있어
정말로?
Really?
How do you know that all
this isn't all about Shana?
샤나에 관해 아는지
네가 어떻게 알아?
사실이 아니니까
알리에 관해서 아는 거야
Because it's not. It's all about Ali.
I've been fielding
questions about her all day.
난 하루종일 알리에 관한
질문에 대처하고 있어
Yeah, me, too.
그래, 나두야
어떤 사람들은
좋게 물어보는 것 같아
Some people have been
nice about it, I guess.
어떤 사람들은
저속한 질문을 한다구
Some people have been rude about it.
This girl in P.E.
체육수업을 듣는 어떤 애는,
알리가 생고기를 먹으며 사육됐었는지 묻더라구
asked me if it was true
if Ali was fed raw meat.
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
- 넌 뭐라고 했어?
- 아무 말도
I just bonked her over
the head with a dodge ball.
피구를 하고 있었는데
공으로 걔 머리를 맞춰버렸지
(phones beeps)
세상에
Oh, my God.
It can't be.
이럴리 없어
이럴리 없지. 알리야
It isn't. It's Ali.
This is intense.
과민반응이야
몸싸움의 흔적이 없었기 때문에
알리 엄마의 사인을 알아내기 위해서
She's saying that because
there were no obvious
signs of struggle,
they're gonna have to wait
for the coroner's toxicology results
검시관의 독성검사 결과를 기다려야 한다고
문자를 보내왔어
to determine her mom's cause of death.
사인이라고?
이건 살인이었어, 쯧쯧
The cause of death? It was murder. Duh.
Maybe the cops think that she was poisoned.
경찰은 아줌마가
독살당했다고 생각하는가 보다
How do they know that
she wasn't buried alive?
산 채로 묻히지는 않았는지
그들이 어떻게 알지?
We don't have to pretend like
아줌마가 우리 마당에서
발견되지 않은 것 처럼
행동할 필요는 없어
she wasn't found in my backyard.
We know your family had nothing to do
우린 알리의 엄마에게 일어난 일이
네 가족과는 관련이 없다는 걸 알고 있어, 스펜서
with what happened to Ali's mom, Spence.
Of course not.
당연히 아니지
스펜서네 가족이
아줌마를 죽였다면
I mean if they killed her,
they wouldn't make a bonehead
자신들의 화단에 아줌마를 묻어버리는
바보 짓은 하지 않았을테니까
move like burying her
in their own flowerbed.
Hanna, it's not helping.
한나, 그건 도움이 안 된다
Yes, it is.
그래, 맞아
내게 답신해 줄래? - 앨리슨이
Hey.
얘야
You hungry?
배고프니?
Not really.
그렇진 않아요
I got another call from
Detective Holbrook today.
오늘 홀브룩 형사에게서
전화가 왔었다
They need you to come
in for that medical exam.
메디컬 검사를 위해
네가 방문하길 원한다는구나
What did you tell him?
뭐라고 하셨어요?
지난 번엔 네 엄마의 일 때문에
미룰 수 있었지만
I was able to postpone it
before because of your mom,
but we can't put it off forever.
우리가 언제까지나
그럴 순 없어
I know it's difficult.
힘든 일이란 걸 안다
But it's important.
하지만 중요한 일이야
And I'm gonna be right there
on the other side of that door.
그리고 바로 그 문 밖에
내가 있을 거야
Dad, I don't want to go.
아빠, 가고 싶지 않아요
Dad, please don't make me.
- 아빠, 제발 가게 하지 마세요
- 얘야, 미안하구나
Sweetheart, I'm sorry.
I haven't wanted to push you to talk.
네가 말하도록
강요하고 싶지 않다
하지만 만약 네가...
But if you were...
아프다면...
hurt...
넌 누군가에게
말 할 필요가 있어
you need to tell someone.
다친 일은 없었어요, 아빠
Nothing like that happened, Dad.
저기, 사실은 배가 고파요
You know, I actually do think I'm hungry.
샌드위치가 먹고 싶어요
I'd love a sandwich.
Coming right up.
바로 만들어 오마
새로운 옷들이 필요하다고
네가 말했잖니
I know you said you
needed some new clothes.
I want you to buy whatever you like, okay?
무엇이든, 네가 좋아하는 것을
사려무나, 알겠니?
Are you holding up okay?
잘 견디고 있니?
I've been thinking about you.
네에 대한 생각을 했었어
Wondering how you're doing.
어떻게 지내는지
궁금해 하면서 말이야
Definitely been better.
분명 나아지고 있어
Yeah. Well, I wanted to
check in, make sure...
그래, 뭐, 난 확인해 보길 원했...
Oh, that I'm not popping
pills like breath mints.
오, 난 구취제거 민트처럼
약을 끊임없이 먹어대진 않아
Well, I wasn't going to
quite put it like that.
음, 난 그런 식으로
따지자는 게 아니었어
그래, 뭐, 누구도 그러진 않지
Yeah. Well, nobody ever does.
하지만 여기에서 일어나는 많은 일들에 대해
사람들이 완곡하게 말하지 않더라구
But people are running out of euphemisms
for a lot of things around here.
Okay.
알겠어
Well, let me know if you need anything.
필요한 것이 있다면 알려줘
Andrew, wait.
앤드류, 잠깐
내일 뭐 하니?
What are you doing tomorrow?
I have a feeling you're about to tell me.
네가 말하려는 일을
할 것 같은데
♪ Deep in my heart
there's a fire burning ♪
발신 : 에즈라 핏츠
제목 : 고맙습니다
- ♪ I need you like a drug ♪
- _
♪ Whoa-oh, you keep me wanting ♪
- ♪ Whoa-oh, I've come undone ♪
- _
에즈라가 학생과
교직원들에게 보낸 감사 인사임
극장소녀님이 채팅을 원하십니다
- ♪ Nights with you like tunnel vision ♪
- _
♪ Racing through the dark ♪
♪ Whoa-oh, heart beating faster ♪
♪ Whoa-oh, it tears me up ♪
만약 나라면, 결코 잊지 못할 거야
그 일이 남은 생 동안 나를 따라다닐텐데
- ♪ Ooh ooh ♪
- _
♪ Baby, let's take it too far tonight ♪
누구니?
- ♪ You're my favorite high ♪
- _
역사 과목을 듣는 베카야
앨리슨이 겪은 일은 끔찍해. 걔는 어때?
_
♪ Thinking I'm crossing
the line this time ♪
♪ Taking me for a ride ♪
샤나 프링
_
사랑하는 샤나 프링을 기억하며
♪ I am weak ♪
♪ But Thou art strong ♪
♪ Jesus, keep me ♪
♪ From all wrong ♪
♪ I'll be satisfied ♪
♪ As long as I walk
♪ Let me walk close to Thee ♪
(phone beeps)
트레비스 : 오늘 학교에서 괜찮았니?
_
오랜만이다
LUCAS: Long time, no see.
안녕
Hey.
로즈우드로 돌아온 거야?
So you're back at Rosewood?
Homeschooling wasn't really for me.
홈 스쿨링은
나랑 정말 안 맞더라
네 엄마가 널 가르치고 낙제시키는 건
일종의 승부수거든
It's kind of a game changer
when your mom can ground you and flunk you.
앨리슨에 대한 얘기를 들었어
I heard about Alison.
믿기 어렵더라구
It's kind of hard to believe.
What did you hear?
뭐라고 들었는데?
납치한 사람으로부터 탈출해서...
That she escaped from whoever
it was that took her...
로즈우드로 돌아왔다고
that she's back in Rosewood.
앨리슨은 학교에 돌아오니?
Is she coming back to school?
모르겠어
I don't know.
(phone ringing)
미안
Sorry.
전화받아야 해. 알리야
I have to take this. It's Ali.
신경 쓰지 마
No problem.
나중에 보자
I'll see you.
여보세요, 알리
Hey, Ali.
모두들 어딨는 거야?
ALI: (on phone) Where is everyone?
네가 전화를 받은
첫 번째 사람이라구
You're the first person to pick up.
I'm going in for medical exam tomorrow
내일 메디컬 검사를
받으러 가야 하는데
and I don't want to go alone.
혼자 가고 싶지 않아
Can you please come with me?
나랑 같이 가줄래?
그래, 물론이지
Yeah, sure.
언제 태우러 가야 돼?
When should I pick you up?
- 뭐하려는 거야?
- 난 그저 기다리느라...
- How's it going?
- I'm just waiting for...
네가 시드니와 함께
대단한 일을 하고 있다고 말하려던 참이었어
I was just gonna say you're
doing a great job with Sydney.
She's gotten a lot better.
걔는 많이 개선됐어
It's really generous of you
주말에 걔와 함께 훈련을 하다니
정말 너그럽구나
to work with her on a weekend.
Yeah, it's nice just
to hang out with someone
그래, *죽어서 걸어다니는 소녀(Dead-girl-walking)의
친구인 것 보다는
who sees me more than just a
friend of dead-girl-walking.
나를 잘 아는 사람과 함께
시간을 보내는 건 좋은 일이거든
알리는 어때?
How is Ali?
I don't know.
잘 모르겠어
어떻게 물어봐야 할지,
어떻게 말을 걸어야 할지 어려워
It's hard to know what
to ask or what to say.
정말 정말 미안해. 늦었네
안녕, 페이지
So sorry I'm late.
Hey, Paige.
안녕
Hey.
또 보자
See you around.
우리와 함께 하지 않을래?
Do you want to join us?
그래. 같이 하자
우린 수영트랙에서 헤엄칠 거거든
Yeah. Come with us.
We were going to do sprints on the track.
Really?
정말?
알겠어
Okay.
물 좀 마시고 올게
Let me just get some water.
그냥 거기에
내려 놓으면 돼, 그래
You can just set those
down right there, yeah.
숨 고를 시간이랑
거름 좀 닦아낼 시간만 주라
Just give me a sec to catch my breath
and wipe off the manure.
미안해
Sorry.
오늘 도움을 줘서
정말 고마워
Thank you so much for helping out today.
고된 일이라는 거 알아
우리 엄마가 극성이시거든
I know it's really hard work
and my mom's been intense.
Intense?
극성이시라고?
피라미드를 건설한 사람들도
이거 보다는 휴식을 취했을 걸
The guys who built the
pyramids got more breaks.
우리 하나를 택할 수 있니?
Can we take one?
휴식 말하는 거야
A break, I mean.
한잔의 물과 스낵이거나
I'd be good with either a bottle of water
and a snack or you making out with me.
아니면 너와 내가
잘 해보는 것 중에
목수로서는 유효해
Still with the carpenter.
Worth a shot.
시도해 볼만 한데
식물 덮개나
가지고 나가자, 알겠니?
Let's just get the mulch out there, okay?
식물 뿌리가 드러날 때마다
Because every minute those
plant roots are exposed
우리 엄마는
흰 머리가 늘어난다고
my mom gets another gray hair.
땅 속으로
들어가는 것 보다
Shouldn't your mom be less worried about
땅 속에서 나오는 걸
더 염려할 필요는 없지 않니?
what's going into the ground
than what came out of it?
엄마는 걱정하셔
She is worried.
정말로 걱정하셨지
She's really worried.
철쭉의 자리를 옮기는 것에도
엄마는 기겁을 하실 거라고 생각해
I think her freaking out
about azaleas is just displaced fear.
그리고 어제 엄마는
보안회사에 전화해서
And she calls a security company yesterday
asking about a $10,000 alarm system.
만 달러짜리
경보 시스템에 대해 문의하셨어
그리고 어제밤에는
아래층에 있는 쇼파에서 주무셨지
And last night she slept
downstairs in a chair.
Just can't figure out if
더 두려운 것이
집 밖에 있는지
she's more afraid of what's
lurking outside of the house
집 안에 도사리고 있는지
알 수도 없는데 말이야
or what's inside.
뭐에 대해 말하는 거니?
What are you talking about?
아무 것도 아냐
Nothing.
뿌리 덮개 저기 있다
There's the mulch.
(gasps)
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
I...
나...
스펜서 다가가지 마
Spence, don't get too close.
Sometimes when they
think they're in danger,
때때로 자신들이 위험하다고 생각할 때
녀석들은 죽은척 하기도 해
they play dead.
기다려
Wait.
딱한 일이네. 독살당했어
Poor thing. Poisoned.
What?
뭐라구?
That's so weird.
그건 이상한데
우린 쥐에 대한 문제가 절대 없었거든
We've never had a rat problem.
I don't even think we've ever had a rat.
우리한테 쥐가 있었다고
전엔 생각해 본 적이 없어
Well, this was bought last week.
음, 이건 지난 주에 산 거네
새로운 문제가 있었나 보다
Maybe it's a new problem.
이거 너무 뜨겁다
This is too hot.
입천장이 덴다고 해도 상관없어
I don't care if it burns
the roof of my mouth,
I'm starving.
배고파 죽겠다
음-흠
Mm-hmm.
오, 어떻게 그렇게
먹을 수 있는지 모르겠다
Oh, I don't know how you can eat that.
Mine's actually not that hot.
내껀 사실
그렇게 뜨겁진 않아
아냐, 끔찍하다
No, it's gross.
Ranch and buffalo chicken?
랜치 앤 버팔로 치킨인데?
Well, you know what they say,
넌 광고하는 대로만 아는 거야
don't knock it until you try it.
시도해보기 전엔
말하지 말라구
Oh, I have tried it. Remember?
오, 시도했었어. 기억해?
You made me after Anna
Nordberg's party last fall.
네가 지난 가을에
안나 노드버그의 파티에 따라가게 했잖아
Oh, that did not turn out so good.
오, 그건 그리 좋지 않았어
No, it didn't.
그래, 그랬지
SYDNEY: I'll eat anything
except spray cheese.
스프레이 치즈만 아니라면
난 뭐든지 먹겠어
If it's day-glo orange and from a can,
그 반짝거리는 오렌지색이고
캔으로 되어 있다면
내 입에 들어갈 수 없다구
not going in my mouth.
Take a deep breath for me.
숨을 깊게 들이 마시렴
And another.
다시 한 번
Good.
좋아
You have quite powerful lungs, young lady.
꽤 강한 폐를 가졌구나, 젊은 아가씨
이젠 머리를 기울여주면
Now if you'll tilt your head,
so I can take a look at the place
상처입은 곳을
내가 살펴볼 수 있다
where you were injured.
I want you to come back
in again for an X-ray.
엑스 레이를 찍은 후에
다시 왔으면 한다
The scar tissue may have trapped particles
흉터 조직이
상처를 유발한 물질로 인해
from whatever caused the wound.
미립자들이 끼어 있구나
We were laughing and joking
and then out of nowhere
우린 웃고 농담하고
그리고 나서 밖으로 나왔는데
she totally shuts down.
걔가 완전히
입을 닫더라구
Well, maybe Paige is
scared of getting too close
아마도 페이지는
다시 가까워지고
다시 거절당하는 게
두려웠던 거야
and getting rejected again.
I don't know if it's that.
그런 거였는지
난 잘 모르겠다
What?
왜 그래?
Nothing.
아무 것도 아냐
No, say it.
아니, 말해 봐
It's just I can't help but notice
난 그냥 알리가
실종 중일 때의
that you've been kind of MIA about Ali.
네 태도에 대해
주목했던 거야
너도 그랬잖아
So have you.
Yeah, that's why I've noticed.
그래, 그게
내가 주목하는 이유야
We'll get to me in a second.
순식간에 내게
영향을 미쳤잖아
I haven't seen you
making any frequent trips
그런데, 네가 거기에
자주 가는 걸
over there either, by the way.
보지 못하고 있어
Her mom was found buried in my backyard.
알리의 엄마가
우리 마당에 묻힌채 발견됐잖아
Okay, wait, can we back up a second?
알겠어, 잠깐,
잠시 전으로 돌아갈까?
What are you saying?
네 말은 뭐니?
You think that I'm scared
to get close to Ali again?
내가 다시 알리와 가까워지는 걸
두려워한다고 생각하는 거니?
알리에 대한 감정이
아직 있는 거니?
Do you still have feelings for her?
I don't know.
모르겠어
I really don't.
정말 모르겠다구
It's crazy, isn't it?
이건 미친 짓이야, 안 그래?
We've wanted this for so long,
우린 그토록 원했잖아
a life without 'A' and Ali back.
A가 없고
알리가 돌아오는 삶을 말이야
I thought everything would
feel like it did before.
모든 일들이 예전과 같이
될 거라 생각했었어
하지만 그렇지 않다구
But it doesn't.
Em...
에밀리...
after what happened
with Nate, did you, like,
네이트의 일이 있은 후에
너 그랬니?
find yourself wanting to
know everything about him?
그에 관한 모든 것을 알고 싶어하는
자신을 발견하는, 그런 거?
I received the package from Nate's mom.
네이트의 엄마로부터
소포를 받았었어
I was kind of obsessed with it.
나는 거기에
사로 잡혔었지
I kept thinking what it must have felt like
그 아줌마로부터
아들을 앗아간 사람인
for her to write my name...
내 이름을 적어서 ...
the person who had taken
her son away from her.
아줌마에게 드리고 싶다는
생각을 계속 했었어
And I studied the printing...
그래서 아줌마의 손길이...
kept imagining all the places
닿을만한 모든 곳에
where I felt that her
hands might have shaken.
프린팅을 할까에 대한
검토를 했었어
좋아
Good.
Can you lie back for me please?
다시 누워 주겠니?
You can sit back up.
다시 앉아도 좋다
If you scoot down to the edge of the table
가장자리로 내려 앉으면
내가 더 잘 볼 수 있을 게다
so that I can get a better look at this.
There's no mention of this
injury on the police report.
경찰 보고서에는
이 상처에 대한 언급이 없었어
I didn't mention it,
중요하다고 생각하지 않아서
말하지 않았어요
'cause I didn't think it was important.
It's a significant injury.
이건 중대한 상처야
How was it sustained?
이게 어쩌다 생긴 거니?
How did you get hurt?
어쩌다가 다친 거냐?
차에서 뛰어내릴 때
바위에 긁혔어요
I cut it on a rock when
I jumped out of the car.
Are you saying this was from a month ago?
이게 한 달 전에
생긴 거라고 말하는 거냐?
Are you sure?
확실하니?
Scarring is more consistent with
a slice rather than a puncture.
흉터는 찍혔다기 보다는
베인 것과 더 일치하는데
Like from the blade of a knife or...
칼날 같은 것이나...
I cut it on a rock.
바위에 긁혔다구요
Maybe there was some
metal on it or something.
어떤 금속물질이나
뭔가가 있었나 보죠
모르겠어요
I don't know.
I mean, it all happened so fast.
모든 일이
순식간에 벌어졌다구요
I didn't even feel it.
난 느낄 수도 없었어요
I didn't even know I was
hurt until I looked down
내려다 보고서 피를 봤을 때까진
내가 다쳤는지도 몰랐다구요
and I saw the blood.
내가 어떻게 기억하겠어요?
How was I supposed to remember?
I was blindfolded when it happened.
다쳤을 때
난 눈가리개를 했었어요
Didn't the police tell
you that on the reports?
경찰 보고서에서
말해주지 않던가요?
Are we done here?
우리 끝마쳤나요?
아직 간호사가
혈액 검사를 해야 한다
I still need the nurse
to do your blood work.
And we also have to set up a time
그리고 우리는 또 네가
트라우마 상담사를 만날 시간을 잡아야 한다
for you to see a trauma counselor.
Hi.
다녀왔어요
Oh. Hi.
오, 왔니
What were you just thinking about?
- 무슨 생각하셨어요?
- 아무 것도 아니다
Nothing.
Where's Andrew?
앤드류는 어디 갔니?
아, 옷 갈아 입으러 집에 갔어요
다시 올 거예요
He went back home to change.
He'll be back.
감사의 인사로
저녁을 만들어 줄 거예요
I'm gonna make him dinner as a thank you.
잘했다
Good.
He did such a good job with the...
걔는 그렇게
좋은 일을 했잖니...
with the yard.
마당에서 말이다
Mom? Why won't you just talk to me?
엄마? 왜 저에게
그냥 말해주지 않는 거죠?
Do you not trust me?
저를 믿지 못하세요?
No, it isn't about trust.
아니, 이건
신뢰의 문제가 아니다
Well, then why won't you
tell me what's going on?
그렇다면, 무슨 일인지
왜 말해주지 않는 거예요?
Please, Mom, I don't
want to be alone in this.
제발요, 엄마, 난 이 문제에서
소외당하고 싶지 않아요
I don't want to be either.
나도 그러고 싶지 않다
Ever since they found Jessica,
제시카가 발견된 이후로
I've just... I've had this
sick feeling in my stomach
난 그저...
복통같은 게 느껴지고
and it won't go away.
어디도 갈 수가 없어
A couple of days after Ali went missing,
알리가 실종되고 이틀 후에
Jessica came to the house
and she was convinced
제시카가 집에 왔었는데
네가 알리에게
무슨 짓을 했다고 확신하더구나
that you had done something to Ali.
She said that?
아줌마가 그렇게 말했어요?
But she never went to the cops.
하지만 아줌마는 결코
경찰에 가지 않았어요
Oh, she did.
오, 그녀는 그랬단다
Your father said that he was gonna tell Ken
네 아빠가 켄에게
두사람 사이의 모든 일을 말해서
all about their affair
and destroy their marriage.
그들의 가정을 파괴하겠다고
제시카에게 말했지
So she stayed quiet.
그래서 그녀가 침묵했던 거야
하지만 켄과 제시카는 이혼을 했고
알리는 살아 있었어
But now that Ken was divorcing
her and Ali was alive,
제시카가 본 걸 경찰에 가서 말하는 것을
무엇으로 막을 수 있었겠니?
what was preventing her
from going to the police
and telling them what she saw?
Exactly what you just
said that Ali was alive.
정확히 엄마가 말하는 건
알리는 살아있었다구요
하지만 무덤엔
누군지 모르는 소녀가 여전히 있었어
But there's still a girl
in that grave who isn't.
Someone killed her.
누군가 그 소녀를 죽였지
And Jessica was going
to say that it was you.
그리고 제시카는
네가 죽인 거라고 말할 참이었고
I don't know... I don't know if your father
모르겠다...네 아버지가
had anything to do with this.
이 일과 관련이
있는 건지 모르겠어
I want to believe that he didn't.
네 아빠의 짓이 아니라고
믿고 싶구나
Are you okay?
괜찮니?
Yeah.
응
I can drive to Longbrook tonight.
오늘밤에 롱브룩으로
운전해서 갈 수 있어
Get us food from that Chinese restaurant
네가 좋아하는 중국 식당에서
우리가 먹을 음식을 가져올게
that you like.
What's that?
그게 뭐야?
Can you take this?
이걸 가져갈 수 있겠어?
Give each of the girls a copy.
애들 각자에게 복사해 줘
이걸 외울 필요가 있어
They need to memorize it.
You recorded that?
너 그거 녹음한 거야?
한나, 사람들은
많은 질문을 해
Hanna, people have been
asking a lot of questions.
우린 이야기를
똑같이 맞춰야 해
We need to keep our story straight.
알리, 난 여기 내내 있었어
Ali, I was here the whole time.
아니, 그러지 않았어
No, you weren't.
난 30분간 이 진료실에
앉아 있었어
I was in this office like a half hour
검사가 시작하기도 전에
질문에 답하면서 말이야
answering questions before
the exam even started.
Well, even so, I mean,
어쨌든, 그렇다 해도
who's going to ask you
questions about that?
누가 너에게
그것에 대한 질문을 하겠어?
Somebody will, somebody always does.
누군가 할 거고
누군가는 언제든지 해
And if it's not Holbrook
it's gonna be someone else.
홀브룩이 아니라면
다른 누구든 할 거야
그들이 내가 거짓말을
하고 있다고 생각한다면
Look, if they think I'm lying about this,
it's not gonna be long
before we're all answering
머지않아 우리는 뉴욕에서 있었던 일에 관한
질문에 대답하게 될 거야
questions about New York.
Ali, where did that scar come from?
알리, 그 상처는
어디서 생긴 거야?
넓적다리 상처 말이야
The one on your thigh.
눈가리개를 한 채로 차에서 뛰어내리다
생긴 게 아니라는 걸 알잖아
I know it's not from you being blindfolded
and jumping out of a car.
So how did you get it?
그럼 어쩌다 생긴 거야?
내가 차에서 떨어질 때
눈가리개를 했기 때문이었으면 해
I wish I was blindfolded
when I got that scar.
Did someone do that to you?
누가 네게 그런 거니?
Did you do it to yourself?
네 스스로 한 거니?
Hanna, once you know something,
한나, 네가 뭔가를
알게 되면
you can't unknown it.
넌 그걸 모를 수 없어
Believe me, I wish I could.
날 믿어줘
그래줬으면 해
쥐약의 효능을 보고 있음
_
사람에게 위험하다는 부분
(phone beeps)
알리 : 네게 할 말이 있어. 전화해줘
_
Sorry.
미안하구나
I didn't mean to scare you.
놀라게 하려던 건 아니야
Why are you here?
왜 여기에 있는 거야?
We have nothing to talk about.
우린 할 말이 없어
I disagree.
동의 못해
My answer is still no.
내 대답은 여전히 아니요야
I heard Ali's dad wants to take her away
알리의 아빠가 걔를 로즈우드에서
떠나보내길 원한다고 들었어
from Rosewood.
He spoke to the school about it.
알리 아빠는 거기에서
학교를 다니라고 말했지
Ali doesn't want to go,
알리는 떠나는 걸 원치 않았지만
우리가 걔의 마음을 바꿀 수 있을 거야
but maybe we can change her mind.
I'd be lying if I say I didn't want to see
그렇게 되길 내가 원치 않는다면
거짓말일 거야, 모나
that happen, Mona.
But I'm not going to make it happen.
그러나 내가
실행하지는 않을 거야
Fine.
좋아
I won't twist your arm.
널 억지로 시킬 순 없지
하지만 분명히
해둘 것이 있는데
But just so we are clear,
you don't get to be some sort
of social Switzerland here.
여기가 스위스 사회처럼
되지는 않을 거야 (중립은 없다는 의미)
If you're not with me, you're against me.
나와 함께하지 않는다면
넌 나와 맞서는 거야
I'm not with anyone.
난 누구와도
함께하지 않아
Sure you are.
그렇겠지
At least you want to be.
네가 원한다면 말이야
And Emily's with Ali.
그리고 에밀리는
알리와 함께지
Mona.
모나
I'm just curious.
단지 궁금한 게 있어
Do you ever wonder when
you became the very thing
너는 두렵게 됐던 때가 언제였는지
궁금했던 적 없어?
you're afraid of?
♪ Let it be, dear Lord ♪
♪ Let it be ♪
♪ I am weak but Thou art strong ♪
♪ As I walk ♪
♪ Granted Jesus ♪
♪ Close to Thee ♪
♪ I am weak but Thou art strong ♪
제이슨 : 그년은 성질이 더러웠어.
누가 죽였는지 궁금하지 않아. 우리에게 큰 은
_
빌어먹을 앨리슨을 환영하며!
안녕, 무슨 일이야?
Hey, what's going on?
What is this?
이게 뭐야?
네가 죽은 날 널위해 출석했어!
우린 너 없는 삶을 축하해!
알리, 안 돼. 보지마
그걸 보면 안 돼
Ali, no. Don't, don't look at that.
Maybe I should leave.
내가 떠나야 할지도
It was stupid to think
I could get a new life
죽음으로부터
이제 막 돌아왔는데
새로운 삶을 얻게 될 거라는 건
어리석은 생각이었어
by just coming back from the dead.
Is that what your text was about?
문자는 무슨 일이야?
You're thinking about not staying here?
여기에 머물지 않겠다는
생각을 하고 있었니?
No.
아니
We got the tox screen
back from the coroner.
검시관으로부터
독성검사 결과를 받았어
You did?
그랬어?
What did it say?
어떻게 나왔는데?
Someone messed with her pills.
누군가 엄마의 약을
엉망으로 만들었어
She had low blood pressure.
엄마는 저혈압이었어
They found Losartan in her system,
엄마의 몸에서 로사탄이 발견됐고
which is for the opposite problem.
그 성분 때문에
반대작용을 일으킨 거야
그것이 엄마의 심장을
멈추게 했어
It stopped her heart.
Spencer?
스펜서?
What's wrong?
무슨 일이니?
What just happened?
무슨 일이 있었어?
Did you think your dad did it?
네 아빠가 했다고
생각하는 거니?
It's hard, isn't it,
그건 어려운 일이야
thinking that your parent
너희 부모님이 그런 일을
할 수 있다고 생각하기는
could be capable of something like that.
I know.
난 알아
I keep trying to find a good enough reason
내 엄마가 나를 죽이려고 한
누군가를 보고도
that my mom could just
watch someone kill me
그 사실을 외면해버린
납득할만한 이유를
and let them walk away.
찾으려 애쓰고 있어
It's just there have been monsters
내 침대 밑에 오랫동안
under my bed for so long.
악마들이 있어왔어
And now when they're not there anymore,
그리고 이젠 그 악마들이
더이상 거기에 없는데
I feel like I have to create them.
내가 그 악마들을
만들어 내는 기분이야
There's still monsters out there, Spence.
악마들은 여전히
저기 어딘가에 있어, 스펜서
They just... they might
not be under our beds.
그들은 그저....
우리 침대 밑에 있지 않을 뿐이야
Hey.
Hi.
- 안녕
- 안녕하세요
Sorry, it was really
stupid of me not to call.
미안해요, 전화 없이 온 건
정말 어리석었어요
No, it's okay.
아냐, 괜찮아
Is everything all right?
다 괜찮은 거지?
Sit down, sit down.
앉아, 앉아
I can't stop thinking about Shana's family.
샤나의 가족에 대한 생각을
멈출 수가 없어요
I mean, every time I close my eyes
내가 눈을 감을 때마다
샤나의 할머니가
얼마나 회복할 수 없는지
all I can see is her grandmother
and just how destroyed
그리고 장례식장에서
샤나가 얼마나 허망하게 보이는가
하는 것 밖에 안 보여요
and how empty she looked at her funeral.
How did you know what she
looked like at the funeral?
장례식에서 샤나가 어찌 보일지는
어떻게 알았니?
'Cause I watched it online, many times.
온라인에서 봤으니까요
여러 번요
Aria, you're just going
to have to find a way
아리아, 네 자신을
용서할 방법을 찾아야만 해
to forgive yourself.
(door opens)
Hey.
안녕
Do you want to come inside?
안으로 들어올래?
I can't stay long.
오래 있을 수 없어
What's wrong?
무슨 일인데?
I think if Alison comes back to school,
앨리슨이 학교로 돌아온다면
you should keep your distance.
넌 그애와 거리를
두어야 한다고 생각해
Maybe it wasn't a good idea
for us to hang out today.
오늘 함께 시간을 보낸건
우리를 위해 좋은 생각이 아니었나 보다
It has nothing to do with us, Em.
우리와는 상관없는 일이야, 에밀리
People are preparing for Ali's return
사람들은 앨리슨이 돌아올 것에
준비를 하고 있는데
and it's not with flowers
and "welcome home" banners.
그건 꽃다발과 돌아온 걸 축하해 라는
플래카드가 아니라고
What are you saying?
무슨 말을 하는 거야?
I'm saying your friend
hurt a lot of people,
네 친구가 많은 사람에게
상처를 준 걸 말하는 거야
me included.
나를 포함해서 말이야
And I'm not interested in continuing that,
계속해서 상처를
줄 것인지에는 난 관심 없어
but I'm also not going to out the people
하지만 자신들을 보호할 필요가
있다고 느끼는 사람들과 난 무관하지도 않아
who feel like they need
to protect themselves.
Okay, Paige, wait.
알겠어, 페이지, 기다려
Paige.
페이지
♪ All this noise that comes
straight from your heart ♪
♪ That I wish it didn't start ♪
♪ It churns like voices in my head ♪
Oh, I'm just a friend.
오, 전 그냥 친구예요
I wasn't able to send flowers
제가 꽃을
보낼 수가 없어서
so I was wondering if I could donate
그래서 장례식에 부조금을 낼 수 있는지
궁금해서 전화했어요
to the cost of the service.
WOMAN: (on phone) Well, her grandmother's
고인의 할머니는
been a member of our
congregation for a long time.
오랜 기간동안
우리 교회의 신자이시죠
I'm certain she would want
to thank you for your...
분명 그분이
당신에게 감사 인사를...
Oh, no, no, I'd really,
really rather the donation
오, 아뇨, 아뇨, 저는,
저는 익명으로 부조하고 싶어요
be anonymous.
Is it possible to send cash?
현금으로 부치는 것이
가능한가요?
What are you doing?
- 뭐하는 거니?
- 오, 아뇨, 우린 현금을 받지 않아요
Oh, no. We can't accept cash.
I suppose you could send it
샤나의 할머니께
직접 드리는 게 나을 것 같아요
to Shana's grandmother directly.
Aria?
아리아?
That's not trying to find
a way to forgive yourself.
그건 자신을 용서하는 법을 찾고 있는 게 아니야
그들이 널 용서하길 희망하는 거지
That's hoping that they forgive you.
It was anonymous.
익명이었어요
그 이면에 있는
의도에 대해 말하는 거야
I'm talking about the intention behind it.
And even if they did forgive you,
그리고 그들이 널 용서한다 해도
그 부조금 때문은 아닐 것 같구나
it's not like they would do it
because of a donation.
You're right.
당신이 옳아요
I know this isn't easy.
쉬운 일이
아니란 걸 안다
And I can say this to you,
그건 내가 말해줄 수 있어
because it's what I have
to tell myself every night.
매일밤 내 자신에게
했던 말이기 때문이지
Once you found out about the book...
네가 그 책을 발견한 후...
the only thing that I could think of
내가 생각할 수 있는
유일한 일은
was how to make it up to you.
어떻게 하면 한 번 더
기회를 얻을 수 있을까 하는 것이었어
And I would have done anything
to get you to forgive me.
그리고 네가 나를
용서할 수 있는 일을 했던 걸 거야
But I realized that that
might not ever happen
하지만 (책을 썼던 일은)
절대 해서는 안 되는 일이었고
and I had to be okay with that.
그랬다면 나는
괜찮았을 거라는 걸 깨달았지
What are you doing?
뭐 하는 거예요?
We're playing checkers.
체스를 두는 거야
We are?
- 우리가요?
- 음-흠
Mm-hmm.
And when we get sick of
that, we'll play chess.
신물이 날 때는
우린 체스를 할 거야
SALESGIRL: How's it going in there?
거기 어떻게 되고 있죠?
맞는 걸 찾았나요
Did you find anything that works?
No. No, nothing... nothing worked.
아뇨, 아뇨, 없어요...
어울리는 게 없어요
(footsteps approaching)
(phone ringing)
Hey.
여보세요
그 녹음에 관한
네 메시지를 받았어
SPENCER: (on phone) Hey, I got
your message about the recording.
Can I come over?
내가 가야 하니?
I'm confused.
난 혼란스러워
알리와 있었는데
걔는 그것에 관해서 얘기도 안 했어
I was with Ali and she
didn't even mention this.
She didn't?
알리가 안 했어?
Maybe that's because she asked
me to give out the copies.
그걸 복사해서 나누어 주라고
알리가 나에게 부탁했기 때문일 거야
무엇을 위해서?
What's this for?
Is this Ali's idea or yours?
알리의 생각이야?
네 생각이야?
Hey, it's not just about
Ali. It's about Aria, too.
야, 이건 알리를 위해서가 아냐
아리아를 위해서라고
Well, it's nuts.
미친 짓이야
Hanna, think it through.
한나, 잘 생각해봐
You're asking us to add on to the lies
이미 우리가 말 한 것에 거짓말을 더 하라고
넌 우리에게 요청하는 거야
that we've already told.
But just memorize it, Spencer, okay?
그냥 그걸 외우라고, 스펜서, 알겠어?
I'm not gonna argue with you on the phone.
전화로 너와
언쟁하려는 게 아니니까
If you want to yell at someone, call Ali.
누군가에게 호통을 치려면
알리에게 전화해
I'm sick of being the messenger.
전달자 역할은
신물이 난다고
(sighs)
♪ Now I know we're capable ♪
♪ Dust myself off ♪
♪ In nothing but a headwind ♪
♪ Two steps up and one back again ♪
♪ Rushed in and now
we're stuffed again ♪
No, I got this.
아냐, 내가 치울게
Do you want to talk about it?
이거에 대해 할 말 있어?
There's nothing to talk about.
이거엔 할 말 없어
It's just my friend's being an idiot.
그저 내 친구들이
멍청이라서 그래
(gasps)
Do you want me to...
- 내가 봐도 되겠...
- 난 괜찮아
I'm fine.
I should not be cleaning
knives while I'm angry.
화가났을 땐
칼을 치우지 말았어야 했는데
Losartan.
로사탄
Gin.
이겼어요
넌 어떻게 이 게임을
겁나게 잘하는 거냐?
Why are you so freakishly good at this?
잘하는 게 아녜요. 내 생각엔
당신이 겁나게 못하는 거예요
I'm not. I think you're
just freakishly bad.
Thanks.
고맙구나
말한 적 있는지 모르겠는데
내가 총상으로 부터 회복하는데는
Did I mention I am recovering
from a gunshot wound
게임이 다소
영향을 준 걸 거야
that might kind of
effect my game, you know.
Your turn to shuffle.
당신이 섞을 차례예요
저기, 이제 밤이라고
말해야 겠다
You know, I may need to call it a night.
조금 몽롱해져서
I'm kind of starting to fade.
Oh.
오, 알았어요
Okay.
여기서 자고 가도
혹시 괜찮을까요?
Actually would you mind if I stayed here?
On the couch.
쇼파에서요
My dad is up in Harrisburg
for Mike's lacrosse game.
마이크의 라크로스 경기 때문에
아빠는 해리스버그에 계세요
And I can't really face
going home to an empty house.
그리고 빈 집에는
정말 가기 싫어서요
Yeah, you can use the blanket on the couch.
그래, 쇼파에서
담요를 사용해도 좋아
This is the one you liked, right?
이거 네가 좋아하던 거지?
오, 예. 고마워요
Oh, Yeah. Thank you.
You know what?
있잖아요?
난 괜찮아요
I'm fine.
그냥 집에 가야겠어요
I'm just going to go home.
게임해줘서 고마웠어요
Thanks for the games.
Yeah, anytime.
그래, 언제든지
안녕히 계세요
Goodnight.
잘 가
My dad got it for me.
아빠가 사주셨어
근사한데
It's nice.
Yeah, he's finally coming
around to the idea of us
그래, 아빠는 결국
우리가 여기서 살기로
마음을 바꾸셨어
staying here.
그래, 그 얘기를
네게 해주고 싶었어
Yeah, I wanted to talk to you about that.
네 아빠가 옳으셨을 거야
Maybe your dad was right.
Maybe it would be a good idea
다른 곳에서 시작하는 게
너를 위해
좋은 생각이었을지도
for you to start over somewhere else.
뭐라고?
What?
안전하지 않다고 생각해서야
I just don't think it's safe.
에밀리, 넌 다른 곳에 있었니?
Emily, where have you been?
I walked into that police station
내가 집에 오도록
너희가 설득했기 때문에
because you convinced me to come home.
경찰서로 갔던 거야
- 알고 있어, 그리고 네게 여기 있길 원해
- 정말이니?
I know, okay. And I want you here.
Are you sure?
그렇게 느껴지지 않아서
Because it doesn't feel like it.
난 학교로 돌아갈 거야
I'm going back to school.
And if we just stick together,
그리고 우리가 뭉친다면
모든 일이 잘 될 거야
everything is gonna be fine.
한나가 녹음한 것 줬니?
Did Hanna give you that recording?
Yeah.
응
그리고 외웠어
And I'll memorize it.
하지만 이번이
마지막이야, 알리
But this is the last time, Ali.
Okay? I mean it.
알겠니? 진심이야
It wasn't that big of a deal.
대단한 일도 아니였어
I know that it sounds bad
거의 에즈라의 집에서 잘 뻔했다는 게
안 좋게 들릴 거라는 건 알아
when I say that I almost
slept over at Ezra's,
but nothing was going to happen.
- 하지만 아무 일도 없었어
- 그래
Yeah.
내가 말한 게
마치 임신한 여자가
What I just said makes me
sound like one of those women
어떻게 임신이
됐는지 모르겠다며
who gets pregnant and claims
that they have no idea how
수영장에서 아이가
생긴 것 같다고 말하는 것 같네
and that it must have
come from a swimming pool.
너 괜찮니?
Are you okay?
알리가 사라졌을 때
When Ali disappeared,
D부인은 우리 부모님께 말했어
그 일이 나와 상관이 있다고
Mrs. D. told my parents that she thought
that I had something to do with it.
그래, 그렇지만 부인은
누가 알리의 머리를 쳤는지 알아
Yeah, but she knows who
hit Ali over the head.
She knows that it wasn't you.
- 네가 아니라는 걸 안다고
- 그래 분명하지
Yeah, exactly.
부인은 나를 모함했지만
내가...내가 정말 걱정하는 건
But she was trying to set me up,
but I'm... I'm really worried
우리 아빠가 부인을
멈추게 했다는 거야
that my dad tried to stop her.
You think that your dad...
- 네 아빠가 했다고 생각...
- 그래, 그리고 우리 엄마도 그렇게 생각해
Yeah, and so does my mom.
엄마는 거의 사실로
받아들이신단 말이야
I mean she practically admitted it.
(door opens)
Oh, hi, Aria.
오, 안녕, 아리아
안녕하세요, 헤이스팅스 아저씨
Hi, Mr. Hastings.
Aria's gonna sleep over tonight.
아리아는 오늘
자고 갈 거예요
그러려무나
Great.
Where's mom?
엄마는 어디 계세요?
오, 엄마는 오늘
집에 오지 않을 거야
Oh, she's not coming home tonight.
내가 스파에 내려 줬다
I dropped her off at a spa.
엄마는 며칠간
스파에 있을 거야
She's going to spend a
couple of nights there
to calm her nerves.
마음을 진정시키기 위해
뭐라구요?
이런 일이 있을 때에요?
What? When did this happen?
웬 스파요?
What spa?
잘 준비를 하러 가야겠다
I'm gonna go get ready for bed.
Dad.
아빠
잘 들어, 엄마에게 전화해서
귀찮게 하지 마라
Listen, I don't want
you calling your mother
and bothering her.
She really needs to relax.
엄마는 정말로
휴식이 필요해
- 왜 엄마가 갑자기 결정...
- 경찰이 그들이 하던 일을
Why did she suddenly decide to...
The police came by to finish up
끝마치기 위해 왔는데
네 엄마가 폭발해 버렸다
what they were doing and she snapped.
다행히, 내가 가서
고소는 막았어
Luckily, I was there to keep
them from pressing charges.
Don't worry.
걱정마라
모든 일은 잠잠해지고
엄마는 곧 집에 올 거니까
This will all blow over
and she'll be home soon.
크리스 : 매일 널 생각해. 네가 그리워
티나 : 네게 축복이! 네가 잘 되길 매일 기도
_
섬머 : 실종이라고? 바이 바이! :)
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -